<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>iOS on Yusuke Ohashi</title>
    <link>https://yusuke.cloud/categories/ios/</link>
    <description>Recent content in iOS on Yusuke Ohashi</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://cdn.yusuke.cloud/assets/image/golden-gate-bridge.jpg</url>
      <link>https://cdn.yusuke.cloud/assets/image/golden-gate-bridge.jpg</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 16:16:05 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yusuke.cloud/categories/ios/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>NWPathMonitor</title>
      <link>https://yusuke.cloud/posts/nwpathmonitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 16:16:05 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yusuke.cloud/posts/nwpathmonitor/</guid>
      <description>Introduction NWPathMonitor is a class in Network framework, which observes network status and monitor network interface. It&amp;rsquo;s available in iOS 12 or later.
import Network You must retain NWPathMonitor instances to get callbacks.
class NetworkMonitorViewController: ViewController { let monitor = NWPathMonitor() } requiredInterface lets you observe the specific network interface.
let wifiMonitor = NWPathMonitor(requiredInterfaceType: .wifi) Here is the list of interfaces that NWPathMonitor supports.
https://developer.apple.com/documentation/network/nwinterface/interfacetype
Detect network changes monitor.pathUpdateHandler = { path in if path.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LSP for Swift</title>
      <link>https://yusuke.cloud/posts/2020-04-07-lsp-for-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 18:01:03 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yusuke.cloud/posts/2020-04-07-lsp-for-swift/</guid>
      <description>What is Language Server Protocol(LSP)?  Language Server Protocol defines standardized protocol with which both a text editor or IDE(client) and a language(server) communicate. The protocol is based on JSONRPC. A client(text editor) can implement  Go to definition Error and warnings Auto completion &amp;hellip;    https://microsoft.github.io/language-server-protocol/overviews/lsp/overview/
 Solves m-times-n complexity problems  What is Sourcekit-LSP?  Apple&amp;rsquo;s LSP implementation on top of sourcekitd and clangd sourcekitd is a framework that provide IDE features clangd for c-family languages (C/C++/ObjC) language server supports only Swift Package Manager project  As of Xcode 11.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Abstraction Layer</title>
      <link>https://yusuke.cloud/posts/2018-11-10-network-abstraction-layer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yusuke.cloud/posts/2018-11-10-network-abstraction-layer/</guid>
      <description>I am experimenting a new way for network request in Kiri library. Kiri is Moya inspired abstract networking layer. I was very impressed by Moya architecture, so to learn from it the most, I decided to trace the same architecture by writing by myself, instead of copy and paste. :D
We need to break down client library into three parts.
Request Normally, you have to construct networking request every time. Instead, in Kiri, your network configuration is compiled in one place, like class, enum.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
