<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on Yusuke Ohashi</title><link>https://yusuke.cloud/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on Yusuke Ohashi</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 18:01:03 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yusuke.cloud/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>LSP for Swift</title><link>https://yusuke.cloud/blog/2020/04/07/lsp-for-swift/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 18:01:03 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://yusuke.cloud/blog/2020/04/07/lsp-for-swift/</guid><description>What is Language Server Protocol(LSP)? Language Server Protocol defines standardized protocol with which both a text editor or IDE(client) and a language(server) communicate. The protocol is based on JSONRPC. A client(text editor) can implement Go to definition Error and warnings Auto completion &amp;hellip; https://microsoft.github.io/language-server-protocol/overviews/lsp/overview/
Solves m-times-n complexity problems What is Sourcekit-LSP? Apple&amp;rsquo;s LSP implementation on top of sourcekitd and clangd sourcekitd is a framework that provide IDE features clangd for c-family languages (C/C++/ObjC) language server supports only Swift Package Manager project As of Xcode 11.</description></item><item><title>Jekyll4</title><link>https://yusuke.cloud/blog/2019/09/08/jekyll4/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yusuke.cloud/blog/2019/09/08/jekyll4/</guid><description>Today I upgraded Jekyll to 4.0.0. This is my note from this migration.
The only issue that I encountered is deployment on netlify. I am making use of netlify for staging testing.
There are 2 versions that you may consider when you are also a netlify user.
Ruby Version Currently default Ruby version on netlify is 2.3.6. However, Jekyll 4 requires Ruby &amp;gt; 2.4.0. But no worry. There is a workaround.</description></item><item><title>You need bundler 2.0 or later</title><link>https://yusuke.cloud/blog/2019/05/17/you-need-bundler-2.0-or-later/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yusuke.cloud/blog/2019/05/17/you-need-bundler-2.0-or-later/</guid><description>I faced a deployment issue of this blog.
I am using Travis CI and Dokku to automate deployment. Both platforms are using the latest bundler(for now it&amp;rsquo;s 2.0.1). I&amp;rsquo;ve been using bundler 1.17.3, since I don&amp;rsquo;t need to upgrade it.
Since ruby 2.3.0, bundler &amp;gt;= 2.0 is preferrable unless you have specific reasons, like you are working on Rails &amp;lt; 4.2. I recommend you to upgrade your infrastructures if you are managing them.</description></item><item><title>2018 in review</title><link>https://yusuke.cloud/blog/2019/01/11/2018-in-review/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yusuke.cloud/blog/2019/01/11/2018-in-review/</guid><description>2018 was yet another awesome year.
Commitments in work I worked on building mobile development foundation.
Jenkins CI Exapansion I read this book to learn Jenkins(written in Japanese). Aside from maintaining jenkins, I learned to modify several Jenkins modules, such as Git plugin.(We are using my forked Git plugin now.)
Open API Specification OpenAPI Initiative
Side projects This blog I moved this blog to Linode. What I exactly did is that I moved my blog on docker on Linode instance.</description></item><item><title>Network Abstraction Layer</title><link>https://yusuke.cloud/blog/2018/11/10/network-abstraction-layer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yusuke.cloud/blog/2018/11/10/network-abstraction-layer/</guid><description>I am experimenting a new way for network request in Kiri library. Kiri is Moya inspired abstract networking layer. I was very impressed by Moya architecture, so to learn from it the most, I decided to trace the same architecture by writing by myself, instead of copy and paste. :D
We need to break down client library into three parts.
Request Normally, you have to construct networking request every time. Instead, in Kiri, your network configuration is compiled in one place, like class, enum.</description></item><item><title>Crontab Guru</title><link>https://yusuke.cloud/blog/2018/09/12/crontab-guru/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yusuke.cloud/blog/2018/09/12/crontab-guru/</guid><description>If you use google whenever you write crontab, this website is good for you.
crontab guru
Crontab format is not intuitive. This website tells you how your cron will work. You can input your own cron job in the rounded textfield, and you can check how it works before you start on your server. It will help you avoid significant mistakes before deploying your job.</description></item><item><title>Check npm dependency graph visually</title><link>https://yusuke.cloud/blog/2018/09/11/check-npm-dependency-graph-visually/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yusuke.cloud/blog/2018/09/11/check-npm-dependency-graph-visually/</guid><description>I found the awesome tool to visualize npm dependency graph.
This example shows dependency graph of react-native-maps, which I was investigating last night.
https://npm.anvaka.com/#/view/2d/react-native-maps
2D You can drag nodes, and highlight node with cursor on.
3D You can rotate graph, but 3D doesn&amp;rsquo;t show module names.
https://npm.anvaka.com/ Github</description></item><item><title>Rails or Django?</title><link>https://yusuke.cloud/blog/2018/08/28/rails-or-django/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yusuke.cloud/blog/2018/08/28/rails-or-django/</guid><description>Now I cannot decide which to go. Please write down your comments below if you have any opinion on it.</description></item></channel></rss>